<resources>
    <string name="app_name">LOT5 Tome</string>

    <!-- Home strings -->
    <string name="description">Land of the Five is a tabletop role-playing fantasy game that focuses on both role-playing and combat. Its name comes from the five Major Gods that rule the land. It is in early stages, being played online as well as offline. The game is still receiving minor alterations and changes, but has reached a playable balance. It was created by Francisco \"Mechero\" Alvarez with the help of Ignacio \"Montaque\" Carril.</string>
    <string name="quote">\"Magic has turned to a darker side and evil is slowly taking over different aspects of life.\" - Kriss Hoferrlock, High Mage of the Mages Guild.</string>
    <string name="history">Through the years, peace has reigned the Land of the Five with only minor conflicts sprouting here and there, but as time goes by, a darkness spreads, more and more present. The people are growing restless it seems like a storm is brewing. The Gods have not been seen in many years and the strange happenings have begun to occur, unexplained and unexpected. Small demons have appeared and creatures have become more aggressive.</string>

    <!-- Rules -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="Rolling_Intro">Dice are a fundamental part of deciding what happens in the game and how things transcribe. When a character wants to achieve something with a chance to fail or a range of possibilities, he must roll a dice to see how well he does or what occurs.</string>
    <string name="Rolls_Basic">Different rolls have different names depending on the situation. All rolls are a 1d20 + the stat applied, but the different situations affect the modifiers to the rolls.</string>
    <string name="Combat_Roll_disclaimer" style="Italic">For combat rolls, see the Combat page.</string>
    <string name="Trait_Check">This roll describes if a character succeeds on an attempt at doing something with a chance of failure. The character is choosing to do this on his own will. Not as a reaction or as a defence. \nAn example would be if a character wants to leap over a wall to get to an escaping foe. There is a chance of failure that would lead to the foe getting away. For this, they would have to roll an Agi Acrobatics Check and beat a difficulty of say 10, due to the wall being of medium height.</string>
    <string name="Stat_Saving_Throw">This roll describes if a character is able to defend against an incoming peril that can be avoided with this Stat. The character is doing this as a reaction and defence against this danger, and not as a thought out choice.\nAn example would be if a character is poisoned by noxious gasses, and his body needs to resist the ailment. There is a chance of failure that would lead to being poisoned. For this, they would have to roll a Vit Saving Throw and beat a difficulty of say 12, due to the poison being of decent strength.</string>
    <string name="Bonus_Roll">When a character has some sort of advantage in what he is about to do, he can gain Bonus(+X) to his roll, where X is the appropriate increase to the roll to be made. This can affect Attacks.\nFor example, if a character is going to roll a Int Nature Check to learn of a certain beast, and he has a book of creatures, he gains a Bonus(+4).</string>
    <string name="Penalty_Roll">The opposite of Bonus(+X), it is a reduction of X to a roll due to adverse or negative effects that hinder a characters capability to complete the task at hand. This can affect Attacks.\nFor example, a character is next to an explosion, and needs to roll an Agi Saving Throw, but his laces were tied together by the prankster Rogue, giving him a Penalty(-5).\nBonus(+X)'s and Penalty(-Y)'s add together, leaving a final result of Bonus(X-Y) or Penalty(X-Y) depending if the result of X-Y is positive or negative respectively. The final result is what counts to other effects like Rogue's Cheap Shot.</string>
</resources>
